

Contact

Phone

+1 332 2384863 +92 324 3329192

Emai

mshahzaib101ed@gmail.com

Address

Dubai, UAE

Portfolio

https://iamshahzaib.com/ https://github.com/mshahzaib101 https://www.linkedin.com/in/mshahz..

Expertise

- Javascript / Typescript
- React js / Nextjs / Gatsby
- SQL/noSQL
- AWS / GCP
- Python
- Nodejs / Express js
- Firebase
- MongoDB
- mySQL / Postgresql
- React Native
- Graphql / REST
- Blockchain
- Docker
- Java
- Bootstrap / Tailwind / MaterialUi / Ant D
- HTML/CSS

Muhammad Shahzaib

FULL-STACK DEVELOPER

Hi, I'm Shahzaib, a Full-Stack Developer from UAE/Pakistan with a focus on MERN Stack Development for the last 6 years.

Apart from that, I have two years of experience as a Lead Developer with five developers working directly under me.

I have specialized in responsive web and application development for startups and small to large size businesses. My skill set includes wide-ranging expertise in Javascript, Python, Java, Node.js, AWS, MongoDB, GCP, Firebase, and a whole host of other technologies, and libraries. Whatever your needs are, I will find a solution that fits them.

One of my specialties is taking an idea from scratch and creating a full-fledged platform.

Experience

Q 2020 - Present

Vaionex I Delaware, USA

Senior Full-stack developer

I am working as a Full-stack and Lead developer at Vaionex since last 2 years. Vaionex provides blockchain solutions. I have worked and led some great projects, here are some of them:

- Relysia: It is a BitcoinSV crypto wallet
- Satolearn: It is a Blockchain learning platform.
- Musicart: It is a music NFTs trading platform built on BSV.
- Metashard: It is a database solution for bitcoin transactions.
- <u>ApiAndMe:</u> It helps to connect APIs to the world with bitcoin micropayments.
- <u>Dojo Discover:</u> It is a platform where investors can invest in Web 3.0 startups.

2019 - 2020

Upwork I US

Full-stack developer

I was Top Rated freelancer on Upwork in 2020. I worked with 20+ clients mostly working on Next.js and express.js. You can check out reviews from my profile.

- <u>Upwork</u>
- Fiverr
- Developed 12+ applications following Agile product development methodologies.
- Developed code following common security practices and development design patterns
- Built 10+ custom interfaces using Wireframes

2018 - 2019

Hasati I California, US

MERN-stack developer

I was working as a MERN developer in Hasati, mostly working on React.js and Node.js, building admin panels that handle realtime telecom data.

 Designed and developed user-friendly admin panels on React.js, including an optimized check-out page that increased user clicks, and subsequently customer purchases by 20%

Languages

- English
- Hindi
- Urdu

Skills

- Full Stack Development
- Project Management
- Project Lead
- Database Management
- Testing & Debugging
- Team Lead

- Fixed bugs from existing websites and implemented enhancements that significantly improved web functionality and speed
- Developed dynamic and interactive websites that ensured high traffic, page views, and User Experience, resulting in 40% increase in sales revenue

2017 - 2018

Axiom I Pakistan

Front-end developer

I was working as a front-end developer in Axiom. I was mostly working using MERN Stack

- Performed quality control testing using Jest/Enzyme.
- Collaborated with external programmers to coordinate delivery of 6 new software applications.
- Developed full-stack web applications which processed, analyzed, and rendered data visually.

2016 - 2017

Freelancer

MERN-stack developer

As a freelancer, I have worked on 12+ different projects during this period. I was working mostly on the backend side using Nodejs, Java, and Python.

- Collaborated on the Complexity Score tool, which removed process bottlenecks by assigning scores to cost, time, and compliance issues, increasing efficiency by 72%.
- Developed user interfaces with modern JavaScript frameworks, HTML5, and CSS3, which improved user satisfaction by 31%.
- Designed and developed backend servers using Java and Python for different clients.

Education

2020

University of the People

Bachelor's in computer science

2018

University of Cambridge

Cambridge A'levels UK GCSE

2016

University of Cambridge

Cambridge O'levels